nextberlin.eu 2019-12-22

# Privacy Policy | NEXT Conference

This data can only be viewed anonymously by RAIDBOXES GmbH and therefore cannot be assigned to specific persons. This data will not be merged with other data sources. After a statistical evaluation, the data will be deleted within 7 days at the latest. Further information can be found in the data protection regulations of RAIDBOXES GmbH. These can be viewed [here](https://raidboxes.io/toc/). 

The legal basis for the processing of personal data through hosting this website is our legitimate interest pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.

You have the right to request information, correction, deletion or blocking of your personal data. As far as you should request deletion of your personal data stored by us, we will execute your request without undue delay, unless legal duties for documentation or storage apply. You can object to the usage of your personal data for advertising or market research purposes or revoke given opt-ins at any time.

In case we process personal data of you, you are so called “affected” within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and you have the following rights vis-à-vis the controller:

  * Right to information according to Art. 15 GDPR:You have the right to get information for free about your personal data stored by us at any time. Furthermore, you have the right to have your data provided to us transferred to yourself or a third party at any time.
  * Right to correct any information that is inaccurate or incomplete according to Art. 16 GDPR
  * Right to deletion according to Art. 17 GDPR
  * Right to limitation of processing according to Art. 18 GDPR:At your request, we will correct, block or delete the personal data stored about you, provided that other statutory regulations (e.g. obligations to store data from the German Commercial Code) do not prevent this.
  * Right to data transferability according to Art. 20 GDPR:You have the right to get information about your personal data for free in a structured, current and readable format
  * Right of contradiction/revocation of permission according to Art. 21 GDPR:If you have given us your consent to process your personal data, you can revoke this at any time
  * Right of complaint to the national supervisory authority according to Art. 13 para. 2 lit. d) GDPR:Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, you have the right of appeal to a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State where you reside, work or suspect of infringement, if you believe that the processing of personal data concerning you is contrary to the GDPR.  
The supervisory authority to which the complaint has been lodged shall inform the complainant of the status and results of the complaint, including the possibility of a judicial remedy according to Art. 78 GDPR

In order to process your request (please mail: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#56323722333825353e23222c7b373116253f3838332425353e24373233247835393b)), we are obliged to check your identity carefully. Please understand that we reserve the right – depending on the criticality of the data – to request further information or proof of identity. This serves in particular to protect your personal data from unauthorized access by third parties. We would like to point out that we reserve the right not to process requests that are received inappropriately frequently or without corresponding proof of identity. We will inform you of this in writing (via E-Mail).

**Children  
**Persons under 16 should not send us personal data without the consent of their parents or persons with parental power. We ask for no personal data from children and adolescents, nor do we collect such information nor pass it on to third parties.

**Log Files  
**When you go to our website, web servers log your interaction with the website in a so called log file. Standard log files like ours contain basic information, for example at what time, what pages were viewed, and your IP address. The legal basis for the processing of personal data through the use of log files is our legitimate interest pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. The purpose of using Log Files is to prevent misuse of our website as well as evaluation of system security and stability. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in our server statistical reports. A personal storage of this data does not take place. This data is also not merged with other data sources. We generally store your IP address anonymously, no personal evaluation takes place. The IP address is only completely stored for the traceability of technical errors and hacker attacks as well as for the logging of consents, e.g. in the newsletter subscription.With the exception of the storage for logging of consents, the IP address is promptly deleted after your visit to us. We may process your personal data until our legitimate interest ceases to exist.

We store log files in our server that your browser automatically transmits to us for technical reasons. These are:

  * Date and time of the server request
  * Browser type/-version
  * Operating system used
  * Referrer URL (the previously visited page)
  * Host name of the accessing terminal (IP address, anonymized)
  * For smartphones, tablets and other mobile devices, if applicable, manufacturer/type designation

**Use of Cookies  
**The legal basis for the processing of personal data through the use of cookies is our legitimate interest pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. The purpose of this use of cookies is to simplify the use of the website for users, to improve the quality of our website and its contents. In addition, we learn how the website is used and can thus constantly optimise our offer. Cookies are small text files that your internet browser downloads and stores on your computer. To an extent, cookies pass along information used to automatically recognize you. Recognition occurs through an IP address saved to the cookies. The information thereby obtained is used to improve our services and to expedite your access to the website. Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://nextconf.eu/cookie-policy/) for further information.

For this purpose we use session cookies, as well as persistent cookies. Session cookies are deleted once you have left our website.

You can deactivate or restrict the transmission of cookies by changing the settings in your Internet browser. Cookies that have already been saved can be deleted at any time. You should be aware, however, that by doing so you may not be able to use all the functions of our website.

A list of all our cookies we use on our website is set out below:

Necessary

  * Webserver nextconf.eu
  * video.nextconf.eu

Marketing

  * Doubleclick (Google)
  * Adwords (Google)
  * Dynamic Remarketing (LinkedIn)

Statistics

  * Google Analytics
  * Webtrekk
  * 23video integration

## **Newsletter**

With the following information we inform you about the contents of our newsletter as well as the registration, dispatch and statistical evaluation procedures as well as your right of objection. By subscribing to our newsletter, you agree to the receipt and the procedures described.

The legal basis for sending our newsletter is your consent via double opt-in according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.

**Newsletter Content**  
We send newsletters and e-mails containing promotional information (hereinafter referred to as “Newsletter”) only with the consent of the recipient. Provided that in the context of a registration to the newsletter whose contents are specifically described, they are decisive for the consent of the users. In our newsletters we inform you periodically about the NEXT Conference programme announcements, discounted ticket/hotel/travel offers and further events by email.

**Use of “MailChimp” shipping service provider**  
We use MailChimp to send our newsletter to our subscribers. MailChimp is a service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC, 512 Means Street, Suite 404, Atlanta, GA 30318, USA.

The E-mail addresses of our newsletter recipients, as well as any other information described in this notice, are stored on the servers of MailChimp in the USA. MailChimp uses this information for sending and to evaluate the newsletters on our behalf. Furthermore, MailChimp can use its own information to check these user data to optimize or improve their own services, e.g. to technically optimize shipping and the presentation of the newsletter or for economic purposes, in order to determine from which countries the recipients come.

The data stored when you registered for the newsletter (E-mail address, name, IP address, and time and date of registration) will be sent to a server operated by The Rocket Science Group in the United States and stored there in accordance with the EU-US Privacy Shield. MailChimp uses this information for sending and to evaluate the newsletters on our behalf. Furthermore, MailChimp can use its own information to check these Use data to optimize or improve your own services, e.g. to technically optimize shipping and the presentation of the newsletter or for economic purposes, in order to determine from which countries the recipients come. However, MailChimp does not use the data of our newsletter recipients to write them down itself or to send them back to us.

We trust in the reliability and IT and data security of MailChimp. MailChimp is protected under the US-EU Data Protection Agreement [“Privacy Shield”](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000000TO6hAAG) and is thus committed to comply with EU data protection regulations. Furthermore. we have created with MailChimp a “Data Processing Agreement”. This is a contract, in which MailChimp is responsible for to protect the data of our users in accordance with their data protection regulations on our behalf. and in particular not to pass them on to third parties. The data protection regulations of MailChimp can be you [view here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

Further information about the data protection offered by MailChimp can be found at:  
<https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>

Further information about the EU-US Privacy Shield can be found at:  
[Die Bundesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit](https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Europa_International/International/Artikel/EU-US_PrivacyShield_Daten%C3%BCbermittlungenUSA.html?nn=5217040)  
<https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en>

**Double opt-in and logging**  
The registration for our newsletter takes place in a so-called double opt-in procedure. This means that you will receive an E-mail after registration, in which you will be asked to confirm your registration. This confirmation is necessary so that no one can log on with foreign E-mail addresses. The registrations for the newsletter are recorded in order to be able to prove the registration process according to legal requirements. Therefore we store the login and the confirmation time, as well as the IP address. Also, the changes to your data stored with the shipping service provider (MailChimp) are logged.

**Logon data**  
To subscribe to the newsletter, it is sufficient to provide your E-mail address. Optionally, we ask you to provide your first and last name. This information is only for the personalisation of the newsletter.

**Newsletter Consent**  
You will be asked to consent to the use of your personal data to receive our newsletter as follows:  
“You agree that the NEXT Conference will use the data and information provided by you in connection with the use of the newsletter to inform you periodically about NEXT promotions, tickets, conference news and publications. In addition, we may send you invitations to exclusive invite-only and further events by SinnerSchrader and Faktor 3 Live GmbH.  
We track and process your user behaviour on the NEXT Conference website after clicking on a link in the newsletter by means of a cookie. By clicking below, you agree that NEXT Conference may process your information in accordance with these terms.  
You can change your mind at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the footer of any email you receive from us, or by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) NEXT Conference will treat your information with respect and for more information about the privacy practices please visit the website. By entering your e-mail address and clicking the button below, you confirm that you are 16 years or older.”

**Statistical survey and analysis**  
The newsletters contain a so-called “web-beacon”. A pixel-sized file retrieved from the server of the shipping service provider when the newsletter is opened. Within the framework of this call, technical information, such as information about the browser and your system, as well as your IP address and time of the call-up are collected. This information is used to technically improve the services based on the technical data or the target groups and their reading behavior by means of their polling points (which can be determined using the IP address) or the access times. Statistical surveys also include determining whether the newsletters are opened, when they are opened, and which links are clicked. This information can be assigned to individual newsletter recipients for technical reasons. It is, however, neither our endeavor, nor that of the shipping service provider, to observe individual users. The evaluations are much more useful for us to recognize the reading habits of our users and adapt our content to them or to send different content according to the interests of our users.

**Cancellation / Revocation**  
We may process your personal data until you revoke your consent. You can cancel the receipt of our newsletter at any time, i.e. revoke your consent. At the same time, your consent to sending it via MailChimp and the statistical analyzes expire. A separate revocation of the dispatch via MailChimp or the statistical evaluation is unfortunately not possible.  
A link to cancel the newsletter can be found at the end of each newsletter.  
For instructions to take this step, please refer to the confirmation e-mail and each newsletter.

## Web Analysis

For the purpose of demand-oriented design, business management evaluation and control of the website and the continuous optimisation of our pages, we use the services described below on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. We may process your personal data until our legitimate interest ceases to exist.

**Use of Google Analytics with anonymisation**  
Based on our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in analysis, optimisation and economic analysis), we set a high value on the quality of our services. Operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR) Google Analytics, a web analytics service of Google LLC (“Google”). The use includes the “Universal Analytics” operating mode.  
Google uses cookies. The information generated by the cookie about usage of the online offer by the users are usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus offers a guarantee of compliance with the European data protection law  
([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)).

Google uses this information at the request of, and on behalf of, the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website, to create reports on the website activities, and to provide the website’s operator with additional services connected with the use of the website and the Internet.  
Pseudonymous user profiles can be created from the processed data.

We only use Google Analytics with IP anonymisation enabled. This means that the IP address of the users will be transferred by Google within Member States of the European Union or in other States Parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the whole IP address will be first transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there.

The IP address transmitted by the user’s browser is not merged with other Google data. Users can prevent the storage of cookies by setting their browser software accordingly. In addition, you can disable the cookie’s sending of the data it has created concerning your use of this website (including your IP address) to Google and the processing of this data by Google if you download and install the browser plugin that is available under the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

Our legitimate interest in data processing also lies in these purposes. The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is § 15 para. 3 TMG and Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. The data sent by us and linked to cookies, user-identifiers (e.g. User-IDs) or advertising-identifiers are automatically deleted after 26 months. Data whose retention period has been reached is automatically deleted once a month.

We also use the technical extension “Google Signals”, which enables cross-device tracking. This makes it possible to assign an individual website visitor to different end devices. However, this only happens if the visitor has logged in to a Google service when visiting a website and has activated the option “personalized advertising” in his Google account settings at the same time. Even then, however, no personal data or user profiles are accessible to us; they remain anonymous to us. If you do not want “Google Signals” to be used, you can disable the “Personalized advertising” option in your Google Account preferences.

Further information on data use by Google, setting and objection options can be found at the websites of Google: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners>(“Use of data by Google when you use websites or apps of our partners”),<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=en>(“Use of data for advertising purposes”),<https://adssettings.google.de/authenticated>(“Manage information Google uses to show you advertisements”).

We use Crazy Egg, a web analytics service provided by Crazy Egg (Crazy Egg, Inc.). Crazy Egg uses cookies that enable us to analyze your use of our website. This process collects and saves data that we use to create usage profiles based on pseudonyms. These profiles are used to analyze visitor behavior and adapt our offerings and design based on user needs. Without your express consent, the pseudonymized usage profiles will not be merged with other personal information that we may have received from you. The data generated by cookies about your use of our website (including your IP address) is transferred to a Crazy Egg server in the USA and stored there. Crazy Egg uses this data to evaluate your use of the website, to generate reports on website activities for [nextconf.eu](https://nextconf.eu/), and to provide other services associated with website and internet use. You may opt-out of the collection and storage of your information by Crazy Egg at any time by following the instructions under the following link: Opt-out here ([https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out))

**Use of Google Adwords**  
For purposes of promotion, our website also employs the Google ad tool “Google-Adwords”. As part of this, our website employs the analysis service “Conversion-Tracking” from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA, hereinafter referred to as “Google“. If you access our site by way of a Google ad, a cookie is placed on your computer. These so-called “conversion cookies” cease to be active after 30 days and are not used to identify you personally. If you visit certain pages of our website while the cookie is still active, we and Google know that you, as user, have clicked on ads placed on Google and were redirected to our site.

Google uses the information obtained through “conversion cookies” to compile statistics for our website. These statistics tell us the total number of users who have clicked on our ad as well as which pages of our site were then accessed by each user. However, neither we nor other advertisers who use “Google-Adwords” receive any kind of information that can be used to personally identify users.

You can prevent the installation of “conversion cookies” by making the appropriate change to your browser settings, for example by setting your browser so that the automatic placement of cookies is deactivated or by blocking cookies from the domain “googleadservices.com“.

You can obtain the relevant data privacy policy from Google at the following link:  
<https://services.google.com/sitestats/de.html>

**Use of Google DoubleClick**  
DoubleClick by Google is a service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). DoubleClick by Google utilizes cookies to present you with relevant advertising. Your browser is assigned an ID number (ID) as a pseudonym in order to check which advertisements have been shown in your browser and which advertisements have been clicked on. The cookies do not contain any personal information. The use of DoubleClick cookies only enables Google and its partner websites to display advertisements based on previous visits to our and other websites on the Internet. The information generated by the cookies is transferred to a server in the USA and saved there by Google. Google complies with the stipulations of the “US-Privacy Shield” agreement and is registered with the US Department of Commerce’s “Privacy Shield” program. Google only transfers data to third parties when legally required to do so or as part of the contractual data processing. Google will never combine your data with any other data recorded by Google.

Through the use of our websites you declare that you accept the processing of the data collected about you by Google and the manner described previously as well as for the previously described purpose. You may configure your browser software to prevent saving cookies; However, we wish to note that in this case you may not be able to use all of the functions of our websites to their full extent. Furthermore, you may also prevent the recording of the data generated by the cookies regarding your use of the websites and its transfer to Google along with the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the DoubleClick deactivation plug-in available via [the following link](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en-GB). Alternatively, you can also deactivate the DoubleClick cookies on the Digital Advertising Alliance website via [the following link](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/).

**Use of Webtrekk**  
On our site, we use components of Webtrekk GmbH, Robert-Koch-Platz 4, 10115 Berlin. These components collect and store data from every single visit to the site for the purposes of marketing and enhancement. This data can then be used to generate pseudonymised user profiles via the deployment of cookies. These user profiles can assist with the analysis of visitor behaviour and may be evaluated in order to improve our Internet provision and to enable us to design our site in a way that meets user needs. Cookies are small text files which are stored locally in the cache of the Internet browser of the site visitor to enable recognition of the Internet browser used. Data collected in this manner is not used to identify visitors to the website personally without their explicit consent. Data is also not collated with personal information or with information regarding the bearer of the pseudonym. You may withdraw your future consent for the collection and storage of data at any time. In order to withdraw consent for the storage of your data, please visit  <https://www.webtrekk.com/de/index/opt-out-webtrekk/abmeldung-vom-tracking/>.

Withdrawal of consent stores an opt-out cookie on your end device. If you delete your cookies, you will need to click on the link once more.

**Use of LinkedIn Conversion Tracking**  
We use analysis and conversion tracking technology of the LinkedIn platform on our website. With the aforementioned LinkedIn technology, you can see more relevant advertising based on your interests. LinkedIn also provides us with aggregated and anonymous reports of ad activity and information about how you interact with our website. Further information on data protection at LinkedIn can be found here: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy#choices-oblig>.

You can contradict to the analysis of your usage behaviour by LinkedIn and the display of interest-based recommendations (“Opt-Out”); click on the field “Reject on LinkedIn” (for LinkedIn members) or “Reject” (for other users) under the following link: <https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out>

## Link to third parties

**Facebook Connect**  
To authenticate everyone who votes and proposes on our website we use Facebook Connect provided by the social network facebook.com, operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). Once you allow the site to connect with Facebook, you will be able to propose a speaker or vote for a proposal and you will be able to publish your activity on the site to your Facebook profile. Whenever you do anything on the site that you might want to publish to Facebook you will be asked whether you want to publish that activity on your Facebook news feed. No Facebook news feed and/or other stories about actions you take on the site will be generated or published without your permission.

Additionally, by using Connect, you permit the site to: access Facebook information related to you (including your profile information, friends, and privacy settings).  
In order to make Connect possible, you agree to allow Facebook to check your Facebook cookies when you are visiting the site, and allow Facebook to receive information concerning the actions you take on the site (which we will only send with your permission). The information shared with Facebook will be transmitted to and stored by Facebook on servers in the United States. In the event you no longer want the site to publish stories about you, or want to otherwise limit the ways in which the site interacts with your Facebook account, you can always disable this feature by changing your application settings in Facebook.  
This disclaimer applies to information collected by nextconf.eu through your Facebook Connect login; however, your activities on Facebook are covered by the Facebook privacy policy and other terms of use (<https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/update>).

## Embedding of external platforms

We have integrated various video platforms on our website. The legal basis for such processing is our legitimate interest pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 letter f GDPR. We may process your personal data until our legitimate interest ceases to exist. The data protection declarations of the integrated platforms can be found below.

**Use of Slideshare**  
Our website employs components provided by Slideshare.com, a service of SlideShare Inc., 1 Montgomery St., Suite 1300, San Francisco, CA 94104, USA and is integrated into our site using a so-called 2-click approach. No personal data is transmitted to Slideshare.com by merely accessing our website. Personal information is transferred to Slideshare, Google Analytics and ComScore and stored in the US only when you manually activate Slideshare components. In addition, a cookie is placed on your browser. We have no control over data collected by Slideshare.com or their processing operations. Nor are we familiar with the full extent of the data collected, the purposes for which is collected or any storage periods which may be specified by Slideshare.com. Additional information is available at <http://www.slideshare.net/privacy>.  
ComScore (Corporate Headquarters Reston, 11950 Democracy Drive, Suite 600, Reston, VA 20190, USA) stores the data thereby obtained by means of a “user profile”. Analysis of this “user profile“ by ComScore is used to provide advertisements tailored to meet market demands and/or for purposes of market research. You are entitled to the right to deny consent to the compiling and storage of this user profile by ComScore. To exercise this right, contact comScore, Inc., at 11950 Democracy Drive, Suite 600, Reston, VA 20190, USA. Additional information on the purpose and extent of data collection and its processing by comScore can be found at <http://www.comscore.com/ger/Ueber_Uns/Datenschutz>

**Use of 23Video**  
Our website uses the TwentyThree™ video marketing platform (“the Service”) operated by TwentyThree ApS, Sortedam Dossering 5D, 2200 Copenhagen N, Denmark. TwentyThree™ is a hosted software-as-a-service tool used for managing and distributing online video. The Service is developed and maintained by TwentyThree™ (“TwentyThree” or “the Company”). When you load a page on our website, the integrated TwentyThree™ player establishes a connection to TwentyThree™ in order to ensure the technical transmission of the video or audio file. When the connection to TwentyThree™ is established, data is transferred to TwentyThree™.  
For information about the scope and purpose of data collection, the further processing and use of the data by TwentyThree™ and your rights and the settings you can configure to protect your privacy, please refer to the TwentyThree™ Privacy Guidelines:[https://www.twentythree.net/policies](https://www.twentythree.net/policies/).

**Use of Vimeo**  
Our website uses the Vimeo video platform operated by Vimeo, Inc., 555 West 18th St., New York, New York 10011, USA. Vimeo is a platform that enables playback of audio and video files. When you load a page on our website, the integrated Vimeo player establishes a connection to Vimeo in order to ensure the technical transmission of the video or audio file. When the connection to Vimeo is established, data is transferred to Vimeo.  
For information about the scope and purpose of data collection, the further processing and use of the data by Vimeo and your rights and the settings you can configure to protect your privacy, please refer to the Vimeo Privacy Guidelines: <https://vimeo.com/privacy>

**Use of YouTube**  
Our website uses the YouTube video platform operated by YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave. San Bruno, CA 94066 USA. YouTube is a platform that enables playback of audio and video files. When you load a page on our website, the integrated YouTube player establishes a connection to YouTube in order to ensure the technical transmission of the video or audio file. When the connection to YouTube is established, data is transferred to YouTube.  
For information about the scope and purpose of data collection, the further processing and use of the data by YouTube and your rights and the settings you can configure to protect your privacy, please refer to the YouTube Privacy Guidelines: <https://www.youtube.com/t/privacy_guidelines>

**Data policy statement for Facebook fan pages**  
The use of this Facebook fan page is accompanied by the processing of personal data. In addition to Facebook, we as the fan page operator also collect and process users’ personal data on our fan page.

Our intention in providing the following information is to give you an overview of the processing mentioned above and also to advise you of your rights pursuant to the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Bundesdatenschutzgesetz (BDSG – German Federal Data Protection Act).

**Data processing on our Facebook fan page**  
When you visit our fan page ([www.facebook.com/nextconf](http://www.facebook.com/nextconf)), Facebook Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, D2 Dublin, Ireland, collects, stores and processes your personal data in accordance with Facebook’s data policy.

Facebook uses cookies to store and further process this information, and these cookies are stored on the various devices of the visitors to the Facebook fan page, especially when the visitors are registered members of Facebook. As a result, Facebook can display targeted advertising on its own platform and also on third-party pages. Facebook does not publish in full and we do not know to what extent Facebook uses the above-mentioned data for its own purposes, to what extent activities on the Facebook fan page are associated with individual users, how long Facebook stores this data and whether data is disclosed to third parties.

Facebook, Inc., the US parent company of Facebook Ireland Ltd., is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield and has thus declared that it complies with the European level of data protection and the accompanying data policies. As the operator of the Facebook fan page, we cannot rule out the possibility that data belonging to users of the Facebook fan page will be transferred to and processed in third countries, nor can we exclude any related risks.

For further information, please also see Facebook’s data policy: <https://facebook.com/about/privacy/>

Facebook furthermore offers the option of objecting to specific forms of data processing; you will find related information and opt-out choices at <https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads>.

We use the statistics services Facebook Insights for the purpose of designing and continually updating our pages as needed. This service records your activity on our page and sends it to us in the form of anonymised statistics. This allows us to gain an insight among other things into the activity of the visitors to our fan page, page views, the reach of contributions, views and average duration of video playbacks, information about which countries and cities our visitors come from as well as statistics on the gender balance of our visitors.

In addition, Facebook records data if you interact with our page as a registered Facebook user (e.g. if you click a Like button, send us a message, or post a comment). These interactions are also recorded and provided in the statistics by Facebook; we as the operator are unable to exert an influence on this. It is therefore not possible for us as the fan page operator to deactivate this function or to prevent data from being generated and processed.

It is not possible for us as the fan page operator to identify individual users or to access individual user profiles on the basis of the insights automatically provided by Facebook.

You can find more detailed information on Facebook Insights from Facebook [here](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/information_about_page_insights_data).

Facebook and we share responsibility for processing the Insights data. The details of this are governed by the agreement on shared responsibility (Joint Controller Addendum), which you can find [here](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/page_controller_addendum).

As the fan page operator, we also process data to a very limited extent only. Our fan page is operated on the legal basis of a balance of interests in accordance with Art 6(1) f) GDPR.

In addition, we store user names and comments that are deleted on account of a breach of netiquette. These are tracked only in order to furnish any evidence that may be required in legal disputes within the period of limitation.

The legal basis for us as the operator of the Facebook fan page to process data as mentioned above is Art. 6(1) b) GDPR (e.g. if you send us a request relating to a contract) on the one hand. On the other, the data can also be processed on the basis of your consent pursuant to Art. 6(1) a) GDPR (e.g. if you “like” or comment on one of our posts or upload content onto our page). You can withdraw the consent you have given at any time with effect for the future by deleting the comment or the content in question. The withdrawal of consent shall not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent given before it is withdrawn.

Facebook has assumed the primary responsibility for the processing of personal data using the “Insights” service offered by Facebook. This concerns the processing of Insights data and the implementation of the rights of the data subject. Please therefore contact Facebook directly concerning all obligations arising from the GDPR in relation to the processing of Insights data. We will forward to Facebook any queries that we receive from you on this subject.

**Use of ti.to**  
For completing our purchasing process successfully you must register on our website after selecting and submitting a ticket order. We use Hypertiny (ti.to) Tito Ltd, 64 Dame Street, Dublin 2, Ireland – the online ticket tool of our NEXTConf conference. You can find the data protection declaration at Tito here: <https://ti.to/privacy>.

When registering, you must enter your personal data such as
